entrust.net 2015-09-09

# Entrust Datacard Privacy Statement | Two-Factor Authentication | Citizen ID

## How Do I Agree to the Privacy Statement?

Entrust Datacard Corporation (“Datacard”, “we”, “our”) values our relationship with you and the other users of our web sites, including Datacard’s web sites located at datacard.com, Entrust.com and entrust.net (the “Sites”) and the services, information and products offered on it (the “Datacard Services”). We recognize that you may be concerned about our collection, use, and disclosure of your personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) that we may collect when you Use (as defined in the [Terms of Access and Use](http://www.datacard.com/datacard-terms-of-use)) the Sites and the Datacard Services. Accordingly, we have implemented this Privacy Statement to inform you of the information that we collect from you, how we collect this information, and what we do with it after we collect it.

By using this Site, you are consenting to the collection, use, disclosure, and transfer of your information as described in this Privacy Statement.  If you do not consent to the collection, use, disclosure and transfer of your information as described in the Privacy Statement, you may not use this Site.

This Privacy Statement applies to the information we collect through this Site.  It does not apply to information we collect through other channels, such as over the phone or in person.  Some of the information we collect through the Sites may be Personal Information that identifies you personally, alone or in combination with other information available to us.  Other information may be non-personal information that cannot be easily used to personally identify you (“Non-Personal Information”)

If you have any questions or comments regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [legal@datacard.com](mailto:legal@datacard.com).

## Are Changes Made to this Privacy Statement?

Datacard reserves and shall have the right, at its sole discretion, to modify, add or remove any terms or conditions of this Privacy Statement without notice or liability to you. Any changes to this Privacy Statement shall be effective immediately following the posting of such changes on this Site. The most recent version of this Privacy Statement may always be found at this URL. You agree to review this Privacy Statement from time to time and agree that any subsequent Use by you of the Sites following changes to this Privacy Statement shall constitute your acceptance of all such changes. This Privacy Statement was last modified on August 7, 2015.

## The Type of Information We Collect

_Personal Information_. We collect Personal Information from you. As explained above, Personal Information is information that can be used to identify you individually, such as your name, business name, mailing address, phone number, e-mail address, credit card number, resume and financial information.  In the event that you purchase digital certificates from our Sites, we also collect identity information that is required to issue digital certificates.  Information required for the digital certificates is either voluntarily submitted by you or is obtained from a third party database during the validation process.  Identity information that is embedded in an issued digital certificate, that is necessary for the digital certificate’s operation, is considered public information and is not considered Personal Information for purposes of this Privacy Statement.  In the context of this Privacy Statement, Personal Information does not include name, title, business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization.

_Non-Personal Information_. We also collect Non-Personal Information from you. This information cannot be easily used to personally identify you, such as your browser type, the URL of the previous web site you visited, your ISP, operating system, and the Internet protocol (IP) Address of your computing device.

## Terms of Access and Use

You have read, understand and agree to all of the terms and conditions of our Terms of Access and Use, which is available at [Terms of Access and Use](http://www.datacard.com/datacard-terms-of-use).

## Confidentiality and Transmissions over the Internet

The transmission of data or information (including communications by e-mail) over the Internet or other publicly accessible networks is not secure, and is subject to possible loss, interception or alteration while in transit. Accordingly, we do not assume any liability for any damage you may experience or costs you may incur as a result of any transmissions over the Internet or other publicly accessible networks, such as, but not limited to, transmissions involving the exchange of e-mail and credit card numbers with us (including those which may contain your personal information). While we will take commercially reasonable efforts to safeguard the privacy of the information you provide us and treat such information in accordance with this Privacy Statement, in no event will the information you provide to us be deemed to be confidential, create any fiduciary obligations to you on our part, or result in any liability to you on our part in the event that such information is inadvertently released by us or accessed by third parties without our consent.

## How and When We Collect This Information

_Providing Information to Us_. We collect Personal Information from you when you provide it to us. For example, if you purchase a product or service sold through our Site, we collect your name, mailing address, telephone number, credit card number, and email address. If you sign up to receive a newsletter, we will collect your email address. If you provide us employment related information, we will collect your name, address, phone number, email address, resume and possibly equal employment opportunity data.

_Communications With Us_. If you communicate with us regarding our Datacard Services, we will collect any information that you provide to us in any such communication.

_Analytic and Reporting Technologies_. Like the operators of most web sites, we use analytic and reporting technologies to record Non-Personal Information such as Internet domain and host names, IP addresses, browser software and operating system types, clickstream patterns, and the dates and times that the Sites and the Datacard Services are accessed.

## How We Use The Information We Gather

Generally, we use the information we collect through this Site:

  * to provide the information, products and services you request;
  * to provide you with effective customer service;
  * to contact you with information and notices related to your use of this Site;
  * to contact you with special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you;
  * to invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us;
  * to improve the content, functionality and usability of this Site;
  * to better understand your needs and interests;
  * to improve our products and services;
  * to improve our marketing and promotional efforts; and
  * for any other purpose identified in an applicable notice, communication, click-through agreement or other agreement between you and us.

## When Do We Disclose Your Information to Third Parties

Generally speaking, we do not disclose your information to third parties. In some instances, however, we reserve the right to do so because it is necessary to the operation and continued growth of our business or to protect the rights of others. You understand and agree that we are not required to provide you with advance notice and do not require your consent to make such disclosure. These instances are discussed below:

_Disclosure to Successors_. We may disclose your Personal Information to any successor-in-interest of ours, such as, but not limited to, a company that acquires us.

_Disclosure to Unaffiliated Third Parties_. We may disclose your Personal Information to prevent an emergency, to protect or enforce our rights, to protect or enforce the rights of a third party, or as required or permitted by law (including, without limitation, to comply with a subpoena or court order).  We may also disclose your Personal Information to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to protect the security of the Site; or to enforce or apply our online Terms of Access and Use or other agreements.

_Disclosure to Affiliates_.  Datacard may share the information collected through the Sites with other Datacard entities, including but not limited to, Entrust, Inc. and Entrust Limited.  These affiliate companies are permitted to use your information for their own marketing purposes and in a manner otherwise consistent with this Privacy Statement.

_Disclosure to Third-Party Service Providers_. We may contract with various third parties and provide your Personal Information to those parties. For example, we use a third-party to process payments made to us, and may subcontract out manufacturing, fulfillment, or other operations. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent such third parties from disclosing your Personal Information, except for the purpose of providing the services in question. However, we cannot guarantee and are not liable for the conduct of such third parties.

_Disclosure of Non-Personal Information_. We will disclose Non-Personal Information, usually in aggregate form, to potential strategic partners, advertisers, investors, customers, and others. You may not “opt out” of the sharing of this information. However, it cannot be easily used to identify you personally.

## What About Cookies?

A cookie is a message that is sent to your computer from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Most web sites use cookies.

We currently employ cookies.

The information we collect using cookies and similar technologies is not, in and of itself, personally identifiable, but we may link it to Personal Information that you provide.  If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer.

## Datacard does not support DNT

At this time Datacard sites do not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include ‘do not track’ instructions. However, you can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies, require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Please consult the ‘Help’ section of your browser for more information.

## Does Datacard Protect My Personal Information?

Whenever we obtain your Personal Information, we use commercially reasonable efforts to protect it from unauthorized access or disclosure. However, we are not insurers of the security of your Personal Information. Accordingly, we assume no liability for any disclosure of data due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third party access or other acts of third parties, or acts or omissions beyond our reasonable control.

## What About Children’s Privacy?

Our Datacard Services are not intended for users younger than eighteen years of age. Accordingly, we will not knowingly collect or use any Personal Information from children that we know to be under the age of eighteen. In addition, we will delete any information in our database that we know originates from a child under the age of eighteen.

## Governing Law

This Privacy Statement shall be governed under the laws of the State of Minnesota without regard to its conflicts of law provisions.

## Contact

If you have any questions or concerns about our Sites or this Privacy Statement, please feel free to contact us at [legal@datacard.com](mailto:legal@datacard.com)
